<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Sean C. Crosby</title>
    <link>https://sccrosby.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Sean C. Crosby</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sccrosby.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>P004 Swiss dog dataset suggest owners slightly prefer dog of the same gender</title>
      <link>https://sccrosby.github.io/post/post004/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sccrosby.github.io/post/post004/</guid>
      <description>I stumbled on this dataset on Kaggle of dogs and their owners in Switzerland. With a little help from google translation it becomes clear that there is a relatively substantial dataset of around 6,000 dogs and their owners including dog gender, dog breed, owner gender, owner age, and a few other bits of information. To practice working with pandas data frames and some simple regressions I entertained a few questions, such as, what is the most popular dog color?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P003 Ray Tracing for Ocean Wave Transformation</title>
      <link>https://sccrosby.github.io/post/post003/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sccrosby.github.io/post/post003/</guid>
      <description>Ray-tracing is a common tool in many fields from Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) to ocean acoustics. In fact ocean acoustics are frequenctly employed to study whale and porpoise populations as well as detect boats or submarines. The concept is relatively simple, a wave traveling through a medium will bend or refract as its speed in the medium changes. And this is true for ocean waves, the ones you commonly see ariving at the shoreline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P002 Working with Empirical Orthogonal Functions</title>
      <link>https://sccrosby.github.io/post/post002/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sccrosby.github.io/post/post002/</guid>
      <description>Today I was wondering if I can make some sense of a rather large 60-year hindcast of winds in Washington around the Salish Sea. Could I see what the typical wind patterns in the region are? How can I manage this with a rather hefty 1+GB set of spatial wind predictions? This is a good opportunity to explore empirical orthogonal functions (EOFs), also known as principle component analysis (PCA).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P001 Transitioning to data science</title>
      <link>https://sccrosby.github.io/post/post001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sccrosby.github.io/post/post001/</guid>
      <description>This is the beginning of a data odyssey, re-tooling my background in oceanography to the rapidly evolving field of data science. After 10-years in the geosciences I am interested in pursuing something new, faster-paced, and more lucrative. I decided to write this blog, not necessarily expecting anyone to read it, but primarily for my own record keeping as I learn explore a new set of data analysis tools and whatever interesting datasets I can get my hands.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
